The Evil of the Daleks(Episode 1)
《Daleks 的邪恶》 (第一部分)
Doctor Who (1963) 04x09b
原为《神秘博士》老版第四季第九集
【时间轴/翻译】巴蛮子sz
基于 opentitles.org 英文字幕翻译
（注意：此字幕的时间轴按2021动画重制版重新调整）
Sincro: wyxchari
(Gatwick airport. The TARDIS is beging taken away on the back of a lorry.)
(故事接《无面一族》, 在伦敦盖特威克机场, TARDIS被一辆拖车拖走了)
- DOCTOR: Jamie!  - JAMIE: The TARDIS!
DOCTOR: Excuse me!
打扰一下!
HALL: Eh?
诶?
JAMIE: I wonder if you could help us?
请问你可否帮我们一下?
HALL: My mate likes the wireless turned on at full blast.
我的同事喜欢把无线电开到最大声
- HALL: I have to keep this turned down.  - DOCTOR: Oh, I see
- 我就把我的助听器拿下来了  - 哦, 明白了
- JAMIE: Who's taken the TARDIS?  -  HALL: The what?
- 谁拖走了 TARDIS ?  - 什么东西?
DOCTOR: He means the police telephone box.
他是说那个警用电话亭
HALL: He said 'TARDIS' or something.
但他说的是 TARDIS 什么的
DOCTOR: Yes. Well, TARDIS... That's, uh...
that's another name for it.
对, TARDIS 是...那是另外一个名字
HALL: Oh, foreign is he?
哦, 他是外国人吧
JAMIE: Me, foreign? You're the one that's foreign! I'm Scottish!
我, 外国人? 你才是外国人! 我是苏格兰人
DOCTOR: Uh, that's right. TARDIS is a... is a Gaelic word. Jamie, hush!
啊, 那就对了. TARDIS 是盖尔语的说法. Jamie, 安静
- JAMIE: It's getting further away all the time! - DOCTOR: Yes, I know.
- 它离我们越来越远了  - 是的, 我知道
DOCTOR: Well anyway, it's... it's our property
and we've come to collect it.
不管怎样...那是我们的东西, 我们是来认领的
HALL: Oh, you mean the...uh, the police box?
哦, 你是说那个... 那个警用电话亭?
DOCTOR: Yes!
正是!
HALL: Well, uh... Well, that's gone.
哦, 这个...它不在这里了
DOCTOR: Oh, we know it's gone. That's the whole point.
噢, 我们知道它不在这里了. 说的就是这个问题
JAMIE: ...Its ours and somebody's stolen it!
它是我们的, 有人偷走了它
HALL: Ah, well, I don't know about that. I got a note here somewhere.
啊, 这我可我不知道. 我这里有个记录, 在哪儿呢?
HALL: Yeah, here we are. There.
耶, 在这里. 你看
HALL: "Police Tel. Box. Collection: 3 o'clock".
．警用电话亭 登记时间：下午三点"
DOCTOR: Let me see this please.
请让我看一下
HALL: Been signed for.
上面有签名
DOCTOR: Oh, yes. So I see. Er... "J Smith".
哦, 是的, 我看到了．嗯..."J Smith"
DOCTOR: Doesn't really help us, does it?
这好像帮不了我们什么, 对不?
HALL: Yeah. Well, I just do what I'm told.
这个...我的职责范围只能管到这里
HALL: Better see the airport commandant or someone.
你们最好去找一下机场负责人什么的
DOCTOR: Oh, no. I... I don't think we'd better do that.
不, 我...我觉得我们最好不要去
Um, Jamie, I think we'd better talk to the police.
Jamie, 我觉得我们最好还是去找警察
HALL: Of course I, um... I do know the name of the firm what picked it up.
当然, 不过...我还真知道拖走它的那个公司的名字
DOCTOR: You do?!
你知道?
HALL: Yeah, firm name of, uh... Leatherman.
是的, 商号名字是...Leatherman
- JAMIE: Leatherman. Now that's a clue!
- DOCTOR: Thank you very much.
- Leatherman, 有条线索了  - 非常感谢
JAMIE:  Just a minute. Now, what street do they...?
等一下, 他们在那条街?
JAMIE: Doctor, wait...
博士, 等等..
- HALL: Did you get all that?  - KENNEDY: Every word.
- 你都听到了吗?   - 一字不落
KENNEDY: We'd better get going. Get your money back at the warehouse.
我们得走了．去仓库拿你的钱吧
JAMIE: We should have followed that clue he gave us.
我们应该沿着刚才他给我们那条线索走
DOCTOR: Perhaps. I think we'd better keep an eye on him.
也许吧, 我觉得我们最好盯着他
JAMIE: Why?
为什么
DOCTOR: Well, didn't you notice his overalls?
They were much too small for him,
你没有注意到他的工作服吗? 对他来说有点太小了
DOCTOR: and the top sheet of his clipboard was different to all the others
而且他那个纸夹板最上面那页跟其它页都不一样
DOCTOR: And when we mentioned the police, he became friendly!
当我们说要去找警察的时候, 他就突然变得友好了
JAMIE: Aye. Hey, may...
真是．嘿, 也许．．
KENNEDY: Kennedy to base. Kennedy to base. Do you read me?
Kennedy 呼叫基地, Kennedy 呼叫基地, 你能听到吗
KENNEDY: Kennedy to base. Do you read?
Kennedy 呼叫基地, 你能听到吗
WATERFIELD: Yes.
听到
KENNEDY: The Doctor and his friend are following Bob Hall.
博士和他的同伴在跟踪 Bob Hall
WATERFIELD: I knew they would suspect him.
我就知道他们会怀疑他
KENNEDY: I'll go on to the warehouse.
我现在去仓库
WATERFIELD: Very good, Mr Kennedy.
很好, Kennedy 先生
- DOCTOR: That's him. There he goes. - JAMIE: Oh, no!
- 就是他, 在那儿呢 - 哦, 不
DRIVER: For Hire. Eh?
走吗, 嗯?
DOCTOR: Follow that car!
跟住那辆车
- WATERFIELD: Yes? - PERRY: Perry, sir.
- 谁啊?  - Perry 啊, 先生
WATERFIELD: Oh, uh... One moment Mr. Perry.
哦, 稍等一下, Perry 先生
PERRY: It's here.
我找到了
WATERFIELD: Good.
很好
PERRY: Like me to open the shutters, sir? Lovely day outside.
需要我打开百页窗吗, 先生? 外面阳光不错
WATERFIELD: I have a choice between the sun or noise, Mr Perry.
我在阳光和噪音之间做了一个选择, Perry先生.
WATERFIELD: I regret shutting out one,
but at least I keep out the other.
虽然享受不到阳光有点可惜, 但至少噪音还是被挡住了
PERRY: Yes.
是
PERRY: Ah, I say! That's very good.
啊, 我得说, 这件很不错啊
PERRY: Just come in, eh? Mint condition.
是刚到的? 成色也还不错
PERRY: Eighteen, uh, seventy. Is it?
是18世纪70年代的, 是吧?
WATERFIELD: Approximately.
差不多
PERRY: Don't know who your contacts are, sir, but this is marvellous!
不知道您的客户都是谁, 先生, 不过这件非常棒!
WATERFIELD: Well, Victorian timepieces are my speciality, Mr. Perry.
是, 维多利亚时期的时钟算是我的专长, Perry先生
PERRY: Wish you'd tell me who makes them for you, sir.
真期望您能告诉我是谁给您做的, 先生
WATERFIELD: But then you would be as wise as I,
and that wouldn't do at all, would it?
那样的话你就跟我一样聪明了, 这样可行不通, 是吧?
PERRY: Whoever makes them, Mr. Waterfield, they'd fool an expert.
不管是谁做的, Waterfield 先生, 他们绝对可以骗过专家
PERRY: If I didn't know it was impossible,
I would say it was absolutely genuine.
要是我并不知道这并不可能, 我得说这件绝对是真品
WATERFIELD: And, uh, there was no trouble with the box?
另外, 这个亭子不会有什么问题吧
PERRY: Apparently not. A bit out of our line, isn't it, sir?
看起来不会. 有点不在我们主业上, 对不, 先生?
PERRY: A battered old police box?
一座破旧的警用电话亭?
WATERFIELD: The whims and caprices of our patrons is our line, Mr Perry.
让客户感到新奇、多变就是我们的主业, Perry先生
PERRY: Hmm. Odd though.
唔, 还是有点怪
WATERFIELD: Mr Perry, I pay you the sum of 50 guineas per week, do I not?
Perry先生, 每星期我付给你50金币, 有吧?
PERRY: Pounds, actually sir. 50 pounds.
英镑, 先生, 50英镑
（几尼金币是英国1663-1813年的货币, 1813年之后被英镑所替代）
WATERFIELD: Yes, uh... I hope I may be forgiven...
是的...我期望你能原谅我
WATERFIELD: ... if I believe that entitles me
to demanding less curiosity of you.
...我觉得这些钱能够容许我要求你别那么好奇
PERRY: Sorry, sir.
抱歉, 先生
WATERFIELD: It is, I think you will agree, a princely salary.
我想你也同意, 这笔薪水是相当可观的
PERRY: No complaints on that score.
Long as I'm not asked to do anything dicey.
我对此完全满意. 只要不让我去做一些太危险的事情
- WATERFIELD: "Dicey?"  - PERRY: Crooked. Illegal.
- “危险的? “  - 出格的, 非法的
WATERFIELD: Your candor is refreshing, Mr. Perry,
你还挺直率的, Perry 先生
WATERFIELD: ...even if your judgement of character is somewhat questionable.
不过你对别人的判断有点问题
- PERRY: I didn't mean that...
- WATERFIELD: I know perfectly well what you meant.
- 我并不是这个意思...    - 我完全知道你什么意思
WATERFIELD: You may rest assured,
I shall not ask you to do anything "dicey. "
你放心吧, 我不会要求你做任何“危险”的事情
PERRY: No, sir.
您不会的, 先生
WATERFIELD: I think you are wanted in the shop, Mr. Perry.
我觉得你该去店面了, Perry先生
PERRY: And the, um... the telephone box, uh... What do we do with it?
还有那个...那个电话亭...我们拿它怎么办?
WATERFIELD: Do? We do nothing.
怎么办? 什么也不办
PERRY: Oh, right.
哦, 好的
WATERFIELD: Nothing, except wait.
什么也不做, 就是等着
DOCTOR: This is his car. He must be around here somewhere.
这是他的车. 他肯定就在附近什么地方
KENNEDY: You sure you weren't followed?
你肯定你没有被跟踪吗?
HALL: No! Course I wasn't.
没有, 当然没有
HALL: Hey, you haven't told me
what this little caper's about yet, uh, Kennedy.
嘿, 你还没有告诉我这一切到底是怎么回事, Kennedy
KENNEDY: Counted the money yet then, have ya?
钱已经数过了, 对吗?
HALL: No, not yet.
没, 还没呢
KENNEDY: Or do you think I made a mistake
giving ya two-fifty instead of seventy-five.
或许你认为我搞错了, 我给了你250, 而不是75?
KENNEDY: We thought you might like a little  extra.
我们觉得你可能会喜欢这一小笔奖金
- HALL: What for?  - KENNEDY: You know those two at the hangar?
- 是做什么的?  - 你记得在机库的那两个家伙吧?
- HALL: Yeah?  - KENNEDY: They're outside.
- 怎样?   - 他们就在外面
KENNEDY: You weren't followed!
你还说没被跟踪!
KENNEDY: We'll be ready for them, won't we?
That's what the extra's for.
我们得做点准备, 对吧. 多给你的钱就为了这
HALL: Now listen...
听我说...
KENNEDY: You on one side of the door, me on the other. Right?
你到门的这边, 我到那边, 行吧
KENNEDY: Straight over their heads.
They won't even know what hit them.
直接对准他们的脑袋, 他们连是什么都不会知道
HALL: Ah, not me, mate.
不, 我不干, 伙计
KENNEDY: It's a bit late to argue, isn't it? They're outside.
现在才说有点太晚了吧, 是不? 他们已经在外面了
HALL: Now listen, I'm not getting mixed up in a kidnapping, and that's flat!
听着, 我是不会卷入一场绑架的, 没得商量
KENNEDY: Oh, dear...
哦, 天啊
JAMIE: Doctor?
博士?
DOCTOR: Well, have you tried the door?
这里, 你试过这扇门吗?
DOCTOR: It's the man in the overalls!
是那个穿工作服的家伙!
DOCTOR: It's all right. He's alive.
没事, 他还活着
HALL: Oh, dear... Where's Ken...
哦, 老天, 哪儿去了Ken...
DOCTOR: Ken? Ken who?
Ken? Ken 什么?
JAMIE: Make him tell us where the TARDIS is!
让他告诉我们 TARDIS 哪儿去了!
DOCTOR: No good, he's out cold.
不太妙, 他晕过去了
JAMIE: See if we can find some water somewhere.
看看我们能不能哪里找到一点水
DOCTOR: Hello, this is something. This really is something.
嘿, 这里有情况, 这里真有点情况
DOCTOR: But, why pay him to help steal the TARDIS
奇怪, 为什么付钱让他帮忙偷走TARDIS
DOCTOR: ...and then knock him on the head?
又来砸他的头?
JAMIE: Well, why steal the TARDIS anyway?
到底为什么要偷 TARDIS 呢?
DOCTOR: That's what's been bothering me, Jamie, too.
一直困扰我的也是这个, Jamie
JAMIE: There's no water here.
这里没有水
JAMIE: Hey, that looks a lot of money, Doctor.
嘿, 看起来是一大笔钱, 博士
DOCTOR: It's between two and three hundred pounds.
大概200到300英镑
DOCTOR: Yes, it is a lot, at least for what he had to do
这的确不少, 对于要他干的事情来说
DOCTOR: - put on a pair of overalls and just hang around.
—— 也就是穿上工作服兜两个圈子
JAMIE: Come to think of it, why hang around?
突然在想, 为什么要兜圈子?
DOCTOR: He was obviously planted.
Why not just go off in the lorry?
他显然是受人安排的. 为什么不跟着货车一起跑掉呢?
JAMIE: You found something else?
你找到了其它什么东西吗?
DOCTOR: I don't know.
我说不好
DOCTOR: Yes, this man rolled his own cigarettes
哈, 这个人是自己卷烟抽的
DOCTOR: So these must belong to somebody else.
That's a fair assumption.所以这东西属于其他某个人, 这是比较合理的假设
JAMIE: What's that?
那是什么?
DOCTOR: It's all right. It's only a train.
没事, 那是火车的声音
- JAMIE: A what?  - DOCTOR: Well, it's a train.
- 什么?  - 哦, 它叫火车
DOCTOR: There are carriages and they go on wheels,
on rails, and they're drawn by a stea...
上面有车厢, 下面有轮子, 跑在铁轨上, 它们是靠蒸汽牵引着...
DOCTOR: Hey, come back!
嘿, 回来!
JAMIE: Well, give us a hand!
来, 帮我们搭把手
JAMIE: Aw, not a sign of him. The only chance we had.
噢, 不见他踪影了. 我们唯一的机会啊
DOCTOR: There is this...
还有这个...
DOCTOR: "The Tricolour". It's a coffee bar apparently.
”三原色“. 这看起来是一个咖啡馆
- DOCTOR: And that's not all...  - JAMIE: Well, what else?
- 还不止这点 - 还有什么?
DOCTOR: Well, normally people pull out their matches from right to left.
通常来说人们都是从右往左抽火柴
DOCTOR: These have been torn out from left to right.
但这些是从左到右抽取的
JAMIE: What does that mean?
这说明什么?
DOCTOR: It means we've got to find a coffee bar called "The Tricolour"
这说明我们要去找一个叫做”三原色“的咖啡馆
DOCTOR: and look for a man called Ken or Kenneth
- someone who's left-handed.
找寻一个叫做 Ken 或者 Kenneth 的人, 这人还是个左撇子
JAMIE: Now we've got something to go on!
现在我们可以继续了!
DOCTOR: But it's so little, Jamie. It's too little.
线索还比较弱, Jamie, 或者说非常弱
DOCTOR: He might only have been there once.
There's no guarantee he'll ever go there again.
他可能只去过那个地方一次, 不敢说他还会再去那里
JAMIE: Now, don't give up Doctor. Remember Bruce.
别放弃, 博士. 记住 Bruce
DOCTOR: Bruce?
哪个 Bruce?
JAMIE: Robert Bruce.
(注：苏格兰国王罗伯特一世. 之前领导苏格兰独立运动多年, 最后其地位终于被承认)
KENNEDY: Look, I told...
看, 我跟你说过...
WATERFIELD: And they were not aware that you were watching?
他们没有发现你在监视吗?
KENNEDY: No, they were too busy trying to work it all out.
没有, 他们一直忙着搞明白是怎么回事
WATERFIELD: Good.
很好
KENNEDY: That Bob Hall was a bit of a problem.
I didn't think he'd turn nasty.
那个 Bob Hall 有点麻烦. 我没想到他会变得棘手
WATERFIELD: You didn't hurt him?
你没有伤害他吧?
KENNEDY: Him? You're joking.
他? 你开玩笑吧
WATERFIELD: I can assure you that I am not.
我可以保证我没有
KENNEDY: He's a lot bigger than me, you know.
他比我块头大多了, 你知道吧
No, I just baggered him one and that was it.
没有, 我只是打了他一下, 仅此而已
WATERFIELD: That was what? Kennedy, I must know
precisely what has happened.
仅此而已?  Kennedy, 我必须知道到底发生了什么
WATERFIELD: How badly injured was Hall?
Hall 伤得有多严重?
KENNEDY: Well, a bit dazed, that's all.
就是有点晕了, 仅此而已
KENNEDY He just mumbled something
and made a run for it when they weren't looking.
他嘟哝了几句什么, 然后趁他们没看见就跑了
WATERFIELD: And where is he now?
那他现在在哪儿?
KENNEDY: Well, I went round to his place later.
我后来去了他的地方
KENNEDY:  There he was coming out the front door,
zip bag and everything.
他正从前门出来, 打包好了一切
KENNEDY: He got in a cab and went to Euston.
他坐进一辆车, 去了 Euston
WATERFIELD: Were you able to find another hansom and follow him?
你就不能找个什么人跟着他吗?
KENNEDY: Eh?
嗯?
WATERFIELD: Did you follow him?
你有没有跟着他?
KENNEDY: Yeah, yeah. Don't worry about him.
He's gone up north.
有, 有, 别担心他了, 他去北方了
WATERFIELD: That disposes of that.
那就估计没问题了
WATERFIELD: Now, this is extremely important:
you did leave the matches?
现在, 这个问题至关重要：你的确留下火柴了吗?
KENNEDY: Don't worry about it.
The Doctor found the cigarettes and the matches.
别担心这个, 博士已经发现了卷烟和火柴
WATERFIELD: And you are certain they were the ones
bearing the name of the coffee shop?
你确定就是带有咖啡店名称的那盒?
- KENNEDY: Coffee bar. -  WATERFIELD: Yes.
- 是咖啡馆  - 对
KENNEDY: Yes. I told you, it worked like a charm.
I never thought it would.
确定, 我说过了, 进展非常顺利. 我都没想到
KENNEDY: but you were quite right.
He got onto the name on the matches straight away.
不过你是对的, 他直接就注意到了火柴上面的名字
WATERFIELD: Well, just one last thing, to make quite sure:
好, 最后一件事, 我得确认一下
WATERFIELD: now you are certain that these are the people that you saw?
你看看, 你确认他们就是这两个人?
KENNEDY: That's them, yeah. Yeah, definite.
就是他们, 对的, 对的, 绝对
WATERFIELD: Right. Well, I shall want you to keep out of sight.
You'd better stay in the house.
好. 现在, 你先躲起来, 最好不要出门
WATERFIELD: And on no account are you to talk
to Mr. Perry about any of this.
在任何情况下都不要跟 Perry 谈起这件事
KENNEDY: OK.
好吧
WATERFIELD: "OK."? What does that mean?
好吧? 这什么意思?
KENNEDY: What? Yes!
什么? 好的!
WATERFIELD: Oh, I know that my attitude may
appear strange to you on occasions, Kennedy.
哦, 我知道有时候我的态度会显得比较奇怪, Kennedy
KENNEDY: You want to play the part of the
Victorian grandfather, that's all right by me.
你想要扮演维多利亚老爷爷, 我完全没意见
KENNEDY: Must be a pretty good gimmick.
You pay me well enough.
你这肯定是一个相当不错的局. 不过你给我的报酬相当不错
WATERFIELD: It, uh... helps to sell to our customers.
这...对我们的生意有帮助
KENNEDY: Yeah, sure, sure. You've, uh... never told me
行, 当然, 当然. 你从来...没有告诉过我
KENNEDY: ...what it is exactly you've got
against this Doctor and his friend.
你对博士和他的朋友到底有什么过节
KENNEDY: Some kind of vendetta or something?
是复仇什么的吗?
WATERFIELD: Explanations are not part of our arrangement.
我并没有必要向你解释
KENNEDY: Oh, just wondering.
哦, 只是好奇
WATERFIELD: Imagination is a virtue, but it can become a vice.
想象力是个优点, 但也可能变成缺点
KENNEDY: Mind me own business, yeah. I get the message.
管好我自己的事, 好, 我知道了
WATERFIELD: Ask Mr. Perry to come and see me, will you, please?
让 Perry 先生过来见我, 帮忙叫一下?
KENNEDY: He wants to see you.
他想要见你
PERRY: Oh, thank you.
哦, 谢谢你
- WATERFIELD: Who is it?  - PERRY: It's Perry, sir.
- 谁啊  - 是 Perry, 先生
WATERFIELD: One moment.
等一下
PERRY: You wanted to see me, sir?
你想要见我, 先生?
WATERFIELD: Yes, I have an extremely important
and delicate task for you to perform.
是的, 我有一个非常重要、非常棘手的任务, 需要你去办
PERRY: Oh, yes?
哦, 是什么?
PERRY: I say, you got a new delivery.
咦, 你又有新货啦
WATERFIELD: Y... yes.
是...是的
PERRY: I didn't see it arrive.
但我没有看到它送过来
WATERFIELD: It was delivered last night.
I've only just brought it in myself.
它是昨晚投递的, 我自己把它拿进来了
WATERFIELD: It is, uh... for a new customer.
那是...给一个新客户的
PERRY: Oh, yes?
哦, 是吗?
WATERFIELD: A Dr. Galloway. He's extremely wealthy
and an ardent collector...
Galloway 博士, 他相当富有, 非常喜欢收藏
PERRY: Of, uh... Victoriana, sir?
是个...维多利亚迷, 是吗?
WATERFIELD: No less. I do not know the Doctor personally,
的确. 我自己也不认识这位博士
WATERFIELD: but we have arranged to meet
in the coffee shop, uh... bar, nearby.
但我们约好了在附近的咖啡店, 哦, 咖啡馆, 见面
- PERRY: Oh, the Tricolour, sir?  - WATERFIELD: Yes.
- 哦, 三原色, 是吗?   - 是的
WATERFIELD: Unfortunately, I am unable to keep the appointment,
但不幸的是, 我没法赴约了
WATERFIELD: so I want you to go instead, Mr. Perry.
所以我想你替我去, Perry 先生。
WATERFIELD: Here is a photograph of Dr. Galloway.
这里有 Galloway 博士的照片
WATERFIELD: This is his assistant and secretary, Mr. James McCrimmon.
这是他的助手和秘书, James McCrimmon 先生.
WATERFIELD: Now I want you to ask the Doctor to come to the shop tonight,
我想让你请博士晚上到店里来
- WATERFIELD: say at, uh... ten o' clock.  - PERRY: Ten o'clock, sir?!
- 约在...十点  - 十点, 先生?
WATERFIELD: Yes. Oh, don't worry, Mr. Perry.
I shall be attending to him myself.
是的。哦, 别担心, Perry 先生。我自己招待他
- WATERFIELD: You needn't wait. - PERRY: Oh, right sir.
- 你不用在这里等  - 哦, 好的, 先生
WATERFIELD: The Doctor is notoriously unpunctual.
这位博士是出了名的不准时
WATERFIELD: I fear you may have a long and tedious wait.
恐怕你得耐心多等一会儿了
PERRY: I shall find him sir. Do you want me to go now?
我会找到他的, 先生。你想让我现在就去吗?
WATERFIELD: If you please, Mr. Perry.
如果你愿意的话, Perry 先生
PERRY: And what are you doing?
你在这里干什么?
KENNEDY: I... I can't make Mr. Waterfield hear me. I knocked.
我...刚才 Waterfield 估计没听到我,  我敲门了
- PERRY: He's busy.  - KENNEDY: O.K. I'll try later.
- 他正忙  - 好, 我稍后再来
JAMIE: Don't look so depressed, Doctor.
别这么丧气, 博士
DOCTOR: If only we knew what he looked like, Jamie.
我们要是知道他长什么样子就好了, Jamie
JAMIE: We'll ask one of the lasses in a moment, when things get quieter.
我们一会儿问问某个女士, 要是还没什么头绪的话
DOCTOR: We've got to untangle this, you know.
我们得解开这个谜题, 是吧
JAMIE: It's all quite obvious to me.
对我来说, 这很显然
They're just robbers. thieves, you understand.
他们就是抢劫犯, 小偷, 你明白吗?
DOCTOR: No, no, there's more to it than that.
不, 不, 这事没那么简单
DOCTOR: Why leave that man in the hangar to give us a clue?
为什么要在机库留一个人给我们留下线索呢?
JAMIE: Which we haven't followed up, you know. "Leatherman?"
我们还没有跟那条线索呢, ”Leatherman"
DOCTOR: There is no delivery firm of that name.
没有哪个送货公司叫那个名字
DOCTOR: Not in the London area, anyway.
I checked in the phone book.
至少伦敦地区没有。我查过电话本了
JAMIE: But surely there's more places than London.
但显然不止伦敦这一个地方啊
DOCTOR: Maybe.
也许吧
JAMIE: Do you think this some sort of a trap, Doctor?
你觉得这是某种陷阱吗, 博士?
DOCTOR: Yes, but if only we knew who our enemies are...
是的, 要是我们知道我们的敌人是谁就好了...
JAMIE: Not the Chameleons again!
不会又是变色龙吧?
(注：上一集04x08 The Faceless Ones 中的主要敌人)
DOCTOR: No, something else.
不, 是其它什么东西
DOCTOR: I can feel them, closing in all around us.
我能感觉到, 就在我们周边逼近
WATERFIELD: I've done everything that you've asked of me.
Isn't that enough?
我已经做了所有你要求我做的事情, 还不够吗?
WATERFIELD: Now you must tell me the truth.
Do you hear?! The truth!
现在你必须告诉我真相, 听到没? 真相!
WATERFIELD: But, you must tell me. I demand!
不, 你必须告诉我! 我强烈要求!
WATERFIELD: I'm talking to you! Come back!
我跟你说话呢! 回来!
JAMIE: Oh, if only the laird could see that!
哦, 要是领主看见这个就好了!
JAMIE: Why do I get all the difficult tasks, Doctor?
为什么这些困难的任务总让我来, 博士?
DOCTOR: Because you're so much better at them than I am, Jamie.
因为在这方面你比我强多了, Jamie
DOCTOR: What did you find out?
你发现什么了吗?
JAMIE: None of the lasses here could remember
anybody called Ken or Kenneth.
这些女士们没一个记得谁叫做 Ken 或者 Kenneth
DOCTOR: Oh, dear.
哦, 天啊
JAMIE: Aye. But, they do have a different lot on duty in the evening.
哦, 不过, 到了晚上又会是另外一批人
Now, maybe they'll know.也许他们会知道
DOCTOR: Jamie, I'm being stared at.
Is there something wrong with me?
Jamie, 有人在盯着我看。我有什么地方不对劲吗?
JAMIE: You mean up here Doctor?
你是说这里吗, 博士?
DOCTOR: Is my hair in disarray?
我的头发乱了?
JAMIE: Well, no more than usual.
唔, 没比平常乱
DOCTOR: Do I look strange or bizarre?
我看起来比较奇怪?
JAMIE: Aye. Well, maybe I'm just used to you.
啊, 还好, 也许我看你已经习惯了
DOCTOR: That's some comfort. Look out, he's coming over.
这我放心一点了。你看, 他过来了
PERRY: I beg your pardon.
打扰一下
DOCTOR: Not at all.
没事
PERRY: It is Dr. Galloway, isn't it?
Galloway 博士, 是吗
- JAMIE: Dr. Gallo-?  - PERRY: ...and Mr. McCrimmon.
- Gallo...?  - 以及 McCrimmon 先生
JAMIE: Aye, I'm Jamie McCrimmon.
是啊, 我是 Jamie McCrimmon
PERRY: My card.
我的名片
DOCTOR: Yes, uh...Mr. Perry?
我是。你是...Perry 先生?
PERRY: Mr. Waterfield's frightfully sorry,
but he can't meet you as arranged.
Waterfield 他表示非常抱歉, 他不能来赴约了
DOCTOR: Oh. Oh, dear. What a pity.
哦, 哦, 太遗憾了
PERRY: But, he says if you'd care to come to the shop at about...
不过, 他说如果你愿意到店里来的话
PERRY: uh... ten tonight, he'll see to you personally.
今晚十点, 他会亲自见你
DOCTOR: At about 10.
大约10点是吧
DOCTOR: Oh, yes, uh... We'll be there.
哦, 好... 我们会到的
PERRY: Righto.
太好了
DOCTOR: Right! Right!
好, 好
DOCTOR: "Edward Waterfield: Genuine Victoriana".
Edward Waterfield：维多利亚真品店
JAMIE: Can't be a mistake. Even though he
got your name wrong, he knew mine.
应该没错了, 虽然他把你的名字搞错了, 他倒是知道我的
DOCTOR: I wonder if Mr. Kenneth has found us.
我在想是不是 Kenneth 先生先发现了我们
DOCTOR: "K. Perry Esquire".
DOCTORYes, I think we'll go and see Mr. Edward Waterfield.
是了, 我想我们得去见见 Edward Waterfield 先生
WATERFIELD: And he, uh... definitely said he would be here?
那他...的确说了他会来这里?
- PERRY: Yes, sir.  - WATERFIELD: Thank you.
- 是的, 先生  - 谢谢你
WATERFIELD: You have done excellently, Mr. Perry.
你做得很好, Perry 先生
- WATERFIELD: Good night.  - PERRY: See you in the morning, sir.
- 晚安  - 明早见, 先生
WATERFIELD: Uh, yes. Yes, in the morning.
呃, 好, 好的, 早上见
WATERFIELD: Kennedy? Kennedy?
WATERFIELD: The Doctor is coming here tonight.
I shall want you to help me.
博士今晚要过来, 我期望你帮我一下
WATERFIELD: And you had better put some warm clothes on. Dark things.
你最好穿点厚衣服。有点脏活儿(???)
KENNEDY: All right. You'd better make sure
that police box is well covered-up,
好的。你最好把这个警亭好好遮盖一下
KENNEDY: in case the Doctor starts snooping about.
免得博士四处乱翻
KENNEDY: Yes.
对
DALEK: Who are you?
你是谁?
DALEK: Answer!
回答!